♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next sunday, a.d. ♪
♪ There was a guy
named joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ but his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ so they shot him
into space ♪
♪ we'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
- ♪ the worst we can find ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
- ♪ and we'll monitor his mind ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ now keep in mind
joel can't control ♪
- ♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
Let's go.
- Cambot.
- Pan left.
Hi, girl.
What a cool guy.
A wisecracker.
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
- ♪ and other science facts ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ then repeat to yourself
"it's just a show ♪
♪ "I should really
just relax ♪
♪ for..." ♪
Yeah, let's see
if we can get this on.
Uh, "cd/wp51."
"Return."
Oh, criminy.
Stupid clones.
I really miss my mack.
Hey, crow,
what's this mean?
"Too many
paramenters-wp51."
What?
Oh.
Uh, you used a forward slash
instead of a backslash.
A what?
Oh. Oh, okay.
Cd backslash wp51.
Return.
Jeez.
30 seconds
to commercial sign.
Hi, everyone. Welcome back
to the satellite of love.
Tom servo and crow
are in the middle
of another
user interface war.
Let's watch.
Oh, this is rich.
"Bad command or file name."
Boy, they expect you
to be a machine
to operate this machine.
Oh, and I suppose you'd prefer
a little, animated clown
who would juggle over
to the little file cabinet
and then wink at you
and point to the right drawer.
Well, yeah, sure.
At least I don't have to have
a photographic memory
to get my mac to work.
Both user interfaces
work perfectly well.
It's really just a matter
of the individual's
personal preference.
We think the joke'll be
on tom servo and crow.
NOW HERE. THE PROBLEM
WITH IBMs AND COMPATIBLES
is that they lack the elegance
and intuitive nature of the mac.
Mac products are reliable,
proven, and they always work.
Oh, yeah?
What about system seven?
It's coming!
It's coming, okay?
There were a few bugs
in it, okay?
You can have a lot of fun
with people hopelessly mired
in computer nuance.
Watch this. Hey, has anybody
seen the mouse for my amiga?
- Amiga!
- Amiga? Oh, come on.
There's a machine for you.
Yeah. Hey, has anyone
seen my angus drive?
Commercial sign
in five, four, three, two...
Commercial sign now.
Oh, now this
is really, really neat.
"Unrecoverable
application error."
This is really cute, crow.
I suppose
we'll have to re-enter
the entire
spreadsheet now, hmm?
No. No, no, no.
Just rewrite
the auto-exec bat file
and stick in
the memory manager.
That's all.
Just take a minute.
Don't worry.
...reboot the dang thing,
see what happens.
Yeah, while, uh, tom servo's
rebooting the computer,
uh, I thought
it'd be a good time
to show this week's
invention exchange.
And, uh,
what I've get here--
let me turn it on a second.
Is a new tool to help
expand people's consciousness.
You know, joel,
there's some things
that people shouldn't
be conscious about.
Like what?
Well, like the fact
that their tongues
are just sitting
in the bottom of their mouths
all day, all night,
even when they sleep.
Yech.
Uh, chatter bot,
would you let me finish?
I'm talking about expanding
people's consciousness
about the recycling cause.
That's why I built this audio
animatronic pop can here.
Enough magic
for many evenings.
Yeah, so what I thought
we could do
is use it as a spokesperson
for, like,
recycling commercials
when we get back to earth.
Here's a baffler
worth twice the price.
Yeah, whatever.
Anyway, crow,
let's do that thing
where I make him work
and I'll manipulate the can.
You do the voice, okay?
All right. Okay.
Young magicians
love this one.
Hello, folks.
Remember, I recycle.
Goodnight.
No skill required.
Oh, this is rich.
Stands rigid inspection.
A quality product.
That one stung--
what do you think, sirs?
I think you've got a kooky
screw loose, is what I think.
Oh, we have fun.
Oh, quit your clowning,
itchy mango,
and go and get your harness on.
All of it.
Disco's back,
frog bait, and so am I.
And so is this new
disco cummer bubble bund.
Enter frank.
That's it, baby.
Work that body.
Make it burn.
There you go.
There's a good one.
Oh, another good one,
frank.
Yes. Come on.
You can make a bubble.
You just put your knees
together and squeeze.
Yes. I have seen the future
of hip hop, joel,
and it is frank.
As for your experiment
this week,
it's another in a long line
of gamera giant flying
turtle movies.
This one's featuring barugon,
who's sort of
a giant lizard dog
with itchy scalp.
Take this film
and shove it, joel.
Well, you see, you can press it
back down again, crow,
'cause he's
a rock 'em sock 'em robot--
oh, we got movie sign!
You know,
that cummer bubble bund
looks kinda familiar
for some reason.
Water. The source
of all sandy frank films.
Oh, ♪ d-a-e-i-e-o ♪
♪ e-i-e-i-o ♪
Hey, looks like a kid
wrote this with a crayon.
Oh, I wouldn't for one
negate nagata.
You gotta, though.
Oh, planning.
I hate when he plans.
There's never enough buns.
Music supplied by our own
osaka high school
flying pipers drum corps.
[Dramatic music playing]
♪ Kill the "wabbit"
kill the "wabbit ♪
Hey, I think
I see my laundry.
♪ Kill the "wabbit" ♪
A little background first.
[Announcer]
Six months ago,
an airplane
carrying an atom bomb
crashed while flying over
the arctic ocean.
- Seen in.
- Hated it.
Taped it.
...shattering
the huge ice flows
and releasing from the depths,
gamera...
Bill gamera.
...who had been
imprisoned in the ice
for thousands of years.
Hey, bill.
Free at last,
free at last,
thank god almighty
I'm free at last.
...was to attack japan.
Ooh.
All manmade weapons
proved powerless
against him.
All scale models
were powerless against him.
There was only
one last resort--
the "z" plan.
Gamera was jettisoned
to mars in a rocket.
Again, there was failure.
And deep, personal shame.
...and split open,
liberating gamera
from the capsule.
And maybe, just maybe,
in a small way,
liberating all monsters
everywhere.
Hmm.
Gamera returned to japan
and attacked the kurobe dam,
the largest of its kind
in the entire orient.
So you know it's good.
Gamera must
have a source of fuel,
and so,
from the power plant,
he extracted electricity
to store in his own body.
Weird, huh?
Hmm. Hey.
[Imitates metallic ding]
Hey. What's that?
Hey, it's gamera!
Gamera!
Oh, you know, I thought
he looked familiar.
Look out!
[Men continue shouting]
Oh, dam.
Hey, stop talking!
One at a time!
Quit talking
all at the same time.
[Men continue shouting]
Looks like a big
chicken pot pie, kind of.
Hmm.
Ooh.
I just can't get close
to anyone anymore!
Oh, you men.
Turn off the main switches!
Bong.
Oh, you got him.
Huh. Funny.
In color, I expected gamera
to be more
of a strawberry blonde.
He's kind of a tawny...
Camera puts on 50,000 pounds.
Oh, lunch for me?
Oh, thank you.
[Screeching]
Why does he sound like someone
playing the trumpet badly?
Oh, you mean like
chuck mangione?
Tokyo, I think it's time
to start thinking
about solar power.
Ah, he can't resist.
He's a slave
to his own passion.
Gamera craves
the creamy taste of flames.
Oh, now was that necessary,
young man?
I mean...
Charbroiled city.
[All]
Charbroiled...
Ooh.
Man,
he's got a short reach.
Now bake the city
at 7,500 degrees...
Quick,
get the kc masterpiece sauce.
I think he means it
this time.
Whoa!
Move it.
- Hey, hurry up.
- Come on.
Oh, I'm full.
[Belches]
Oh, you know
what you wanna do is,
you wanna
pull off them petals
and dip it
in that sauce there.
Oh, that's really
super neat.
Oh, yeah.
Try the lemon.
Well, that reminds me.
I should shingle my roof
when I get back to earth.
Huh?
Bye.
Whoa, it looks like wembley
stadium after a soccer match.
Oh, there's a lot of stuff
going on down there.
So...
Oops. That was me.
My fault.
Uh, sorry.
Can't see.
My head's inside,
you know.
Higher, gamera, higher.
About 50 feet up.
Okay, back up and push.
Uh-oh.
A spectacular cascade
of alka seltzer.
I can't believe gamera
ate the whole thing.
He ate it, ralph.
Look, water,
the source of all--
we know. We know.
Ooh.
Gamera loves flames.
But they go straight
to his hips.
He left japan as suddenly
as he had arrived,
and headed for mount uzal
and the equator,
flying directly toward
the flowing molten lava.
He had a contract
with wham-o.
Hmm.
When in cleveland,
visit the golden dragon inn,
only 15 minutes
from our cinema.
And now back to our film--
sky king,
the motion picture.
Tell me, are you really
going to resign?
Yeah.
This is my last day up here.
I will serve my master
down there.
But you've just
earned your wings
after so much
dedicated work.
Clarence.
What made you decide
to quit?
Tired of flying already?
Certainly not.
My dream
is to continue flying.
And have my voice dubbed.
Or else life
would be worthless.
So that's why
I'm quitting now.
- I want to learn more.
- You should too.
So that later
I will be more skilled.
Fair enough.
Hey, didn't george harrison
write this song?
Yeah.
"My sweet warlord."
Oh, that's cute.
33 1/3, I think.
Hey, I never
knew a cheese-cutter
could sound this good.
Oh, it's the joy luck club
blues band.
[Laughs]
Come on. Play it like you
feel it, mr. Eddie's father.
And now it's pink lady
unplugged.
Ah, this ought
to shut 'em up.
Come on.
Oh, they're not that bad.
Uh, gang,
maybe you shouldn't be smoking
around all those things, hmm?
Hmm.
This one kinda
looks like an avocado.
Hey, can the pineapple.
It's somebody.
Shh.
Ixnay.
I'll get it.
Ah, damn charlie horse.
Sitting on my leg.
Hmm?
Super fly?
Oh, it's you.
Got 'em.
Come in.
Tea, biscuits?
My brother.
Hi, I'm dangerous
to myself and others.
Here's all my money.
How much?
It's my pension.
- Ooh.
- 50 bucks.
Not a big help.
Yeah, it's no use
working for others.
I've got to get my own
aircraft company.
- Now.
- However small.
That'll take money.
And you don't have any.
He just took it.
Nah, nah.
Well,
now that we're all here,
I'll tell you the plans.
During the war,
I found a huge opal.
Hmm. Big.
Believe me, it was about
the size of an ostrich egg.
Oh, it gets bigger
every time he tells the story.
Just before I was taken away
to a prisoner of war camp,
- I managed to...
- Did you ever get out?
...again in the cave
where I found it.
That was 20 years ago.
[Loud whisper]
Don't mention the war.
The cave lies deep
in the dense jungle
where even the natives
never go.
I think that it'll be safe.
We'll be taking a big gable.
[Goofy laughter]
Me like gamble.
We'll be able to sell it
for an absolute fortune.
Are you sure
it's a real opal?
- It's real.
- Yep.
It must be.
And there might be more as well.
Since I can't get away,
keisuke, you go.
Name's quesadilla.
- Gladly.
- Yeah.
You will all go
on a cargo boat.
With crutch cargo.
Get it?
False names,
and you'll carry forged papers.
You got them?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
'Course I have.
Cost me a small fortune.
For the forgery.
This is for you.
This one for you.
And the password is...
You two will board the ship
as ordinary seamen.
For god's sake
don't bungle.
In the jungle.
- We're counting on you.
- Thanks.
- Okay?
- Okay.
The awaji maru will reach
new guinea in 25 days,
unload here, and then
continue around this area.
And then it returns back
to the original harbor
just about
a fortnight later.
You three have
got that two-week period
in which to locate the opal.
You mean we're to quit
the ship without leave
and then reboard it again?
That's dishonest!
We say we want to pick up
the bones of our bodies
who died inland
during the war.
Oh, that's rich!
[Loud laughter]
Then when you get
to the airport here,
you'll have to charter
a helicopter.
Keisuke, you'll be able
to fly it for them.
That's why you're here.
And next, money.
Remember to take plenty of
black-market dollars with you.
Make sure they have
art linkletter's
picture on them.
Be careful
of the scorpions.
And whitesnake.
You've had it if they sting.
The jungle is full
of many other dangers as well.
So take these
just to be safe.
And don't run by the pool.
And bring a washcloth
and a ziplock bag
to clean up after baby.
Yeah, and don't
go into the water
until an hour after
you've eaten.
Are those chick jeans?
[Whistles]
Just who do they think we are,
anyway?
Oh, stop grumbling.
Patience.
D'oh.
You, that room's filthy.
So clean it!
Do it yourself.
IT'S TV's MR. T.
I pity those fools.
Working hard?
No, hardly working.
It's the...
Why couldn't you find us
some easier work to do?
Just stick with it.
Oh, help us out.
Come on, huh?
We have to clean
the washroom too.
[Laughs]
It's no joke.
Oh, sorry.
I forgot. I laughed.
Hey. My cabin.
Tonight.
Only three more days.
Are you absolutely sure?
Mm-hmm.
I've got a calendar.
I know.
Don't give it up now.
Okay.
[Imitates inhaling smoke]
Nearing the santana concert,
we put on our love beads
and put down the landing gear
of our vw microbus.
Killer.
Hey, and we're
just in time to see don ho.
And his sister heidi.
All the earth mothers
are expressing
their political stances.
It's quite a stance too.
Wish I had a lawnmower.
Hey.
The male of the tribe
is saying,
"how about dinner
and a movie?"
The female responds with,
"okay, but I've seen
mannequin already."
The male says he just wants
to go to sleep,
but the female
wants to talk.
Can't see.
[Helicopter approaching]
[Shouting]
What, did someone drop
a coke bottle all of a sudden?
Attention all personnel.
Tonight's movie
is the jungle goddess,
starring george reeves, a guy
who looks like ernie kovacs,
and lots of
french fried potatoes.
Hey, we're from america.
We've come to decimate
your jungle,
convert your youth,
and make you feel inferior.
Look, it's robert duvall.
Hello? Anybody here?
You know, I swear
there were a lot of dancers
here a minute ago.
Doesn't make--figure.
Go figure.
Hi. How was your flight?
Hey, quit clowning.
It's probably quite far
to the caves.
Ah.
Ooh. They seem rude.
Hey, get me.
I'm a stranger in paradise.
Big tie.
- Huh?
Look. There's writing.
It says "yankees go home."
It's a guide post.
Not much use
if we can't read it.
Are they words or pictures?
Uh-huh.
Hey, give me the map,
will you?
I think that there might
be a shortcut
through the jungle
somewhere.
Hoo!
Oh, who goosed me?
Pat morita,
denture wearer.
Hey, watch it.
Don't wave that gun.
- We're quite safe.
- Yes, it's a movie.
They're pleased.
They helped us a lot
during the war.
They're good people.
So better let me keep it.
Give it here, huh?
Uh-oh.
I'll, uh, shoot myself
to prove we're friendly.
Hey. Ask one of 'em
to be our guide.
How can I? None of them
understand us.
You're wrong.
I understand perfectly.
Hey, has anybody
called dibs yet?
Dibs. Dibs.
Oh, darn. Darn.
Are you smitten by my eyes
by now?
[Imitates purring]
Oh, it's my dad.
I got to go now.
Oh, it's tom wolfe.
Oh, thank god.
The contemporary novel is saved.
Darn fool kid.
You gentlemen
come directly from japan?
Yes. Who are you?
A doctor.
I've been living and working
with the people of these islands
for over ten years.
He has tenure then.
Tenure.
Our friend the doctor
came with his wife
to study certain diseases.
Then his wife died of the very
disease he was curing.
Convenient.
He decided to stay here
the rest of his life.
We're impressed.
It is quiet here.
I feel now that I belong
to this peaceful village.
I never even think
of my own home any longer.
Not even a little?
And I've been
extremely fortunate,
for karen is my assistant,
and an excellent one.
Oh, we get the picture.
Ah.
Oh.
By the way,
what has brought you
to such a backwards spot?
The wind, man.
The wild wind.
Well, sir, we've come
to investigate a certain cave.
It isn't far from here.
Hmm.
No go, navajo.
Uh-uh.
Doctor.
You know where the cave is?
Oh, you must not
go near that cave.
Believe me.
And why not?
It's called rainbow valley.
The care bears live there.
What is that?
On that stone,
there's a warning to all.
It says "warning."
It forbids us to go there,
and he who disobeys it
will not return.
But why?
Nobody knows.
The trouble I've seen.
...it stood there thousands
of years, so they say.
Only a fool would disobey.
Our ancestors
handed down a warning
that an evil spirit
dwells there,
and it is dangerous
even to approach
the valley of the rainbow.
Go on.
Then no one here
will act as our guide?
Certainly not.
All the people
are begging you not to go.
You must respect their wishes
on this point.
Even his royal
neck brace says so.
All right,
huddle up, everybody.
Bring it in. Come on.
Bring it in.
Darn tourists.
Ha.
They don't anyone
to go near that cave.
What more proof
could there be
that there's hidden treasure
there?
Of course. And they've
even created a legend
to protect it.
The evil spirit
is really the scorpion
my brother mentioned then.
We'll never get a guide
from them.
Ah, I'll have to call
kelly girls.
Let's go alone.
This way.
But what if the treasure really
does belong to these natives?
So?
We're gonna take it anyway.
Okay. Hey, let's go.
- But i--
- let's go.
No! No!
You mustn't go in there.
Wait! Don't go!
[Shouts]
Disturbed native rebuttal.
Don't!
Don't go in there.
Oh!
Hey, watch out!
All right, all right.
I didn't think this gun
would come in handy so soon.
Right.
Now, let's go.
Just letting off
a little steam.
Gotta go.
Oh, we gotta go too.
Nice meeting you folks.
Thanks for everything.
What fools.
...peas and carrots.
And we'll be right back
right after this.
Kids, here's the greatest
and neatest and latest thing--
5,000-piece fightin'
men and monster set.
Some pieces not included.
Astonish and baffle
your friends and foes
while you pulverize japan.
Here's what you get--
500 japanese light infantry.
Body parts
may not be missing.
36 helpless officials,
20 tanks,
15 recoilless rifles.
Not in this set.
24 bazooka gum runners.
18 ambulance chasers.
12 jet fighters.
Stick not included.
16 helicopter parts,
200 shooting crouchers,
19 fighting clowns,
eight deserters,
six geese a-laying,
24 mohawk indians,
and much, much, much, much more.
Act now and receive
at half the extra value
the mystifying
monster action pack.
Flame on with gamera.
Torso sold separately.
He spits real fire
and causes real pain.
Solid rubber barugon
comes complete with optional
ram tongue action.
Not responsible
for nerve damage.
And amuse your friends
with topo, meep song, and bart
the battlin' belgian endive.
Some parts may not exist.
Act now, act often,
and snap on the entire
tokyo metropolitan area,
complete with buildings,
bridges,
and the break-away
mount inuko dam.
Smaller than shown.
Trample the add-on hapless
citizen play set,
then abhor the action
with a fabulous
anti-war protest pack.
Senator wellstone
not included.
But that's not all.
Relive your favorite
japanese movie carnage
with the lights, gamera, gamera
action series.
There's the gimp, the goon,
the shame-filled brother,
the hapless geisha,
and the pull-apart voodoo kenny.
Pose in the nude
with the frisky kitten review,
then watch the action
from high atop tokyo tower
as the twisted world
you create explodes,
in rivers of blood
and endless pain.
Order today.
Offer limited.
Not available in utah,
puerto rico--
price is subject to end.
Please wear rubber underwear,
and some parts
may be made of chicken.
Act now, buy bonds...
Mommy, mommy, mommy!
Okay. Okay.
Breathe, boy. Breathe.
Oh. Mommy.
All right,
that was a good one.
Let's not do that again.
Here's something we think
you'll really like.
Mommy.
[Sobs]
It's all right.
That's okay.
Hey, I found my hamster.
What are we
looking for again?
What does it look like?
Hmm?
Huh?
A bowling ball?
Hey! It's here!
It's here!
Earl anthony's signature.
I'm crying.
Our gamble paid off.
Neat.
We got the opal.
It's ours.
Those men, no wonder
they tried to stop us.
That was fast.
Now we're
multi-millionaires.
Just wait till I get home.
I'll buy a great,
big mansion
and keep all the cupboards
stocked full of food and wine.
Of all the dumb luck.
Uh-oh.
You got a little, uh...
Rubber scorpion.
She'll burst with happiness.
I'll do just
what I please from now on.
- Just think.
- No more broccoli.
You'll own
an aircraft company.
I'm so pleased
I shall go mad.
Onodera,
you say something, huh?
Uh, any last words?
Hey, onodera, aren't you happy
that we found it?
Uh, friendship is worth
much more than the opal to me.
I just want you kids
to be good.
Hiratas, you're
a good friend.
Imagine sharing all this
with us.
It's fun.
Think how happy he'll be
that we found it.
Oh, yeah.
I wish I could tell him.
Hey, hirata!
Ollie, ollie, in free.
We found the opal already!
Boy, is he high.
Excuse me.
Death, where is thy sting?
We're waiting.
[Wild laughter]
What an eccentric performance.
Any minute now I think he--
bingo.
Oop, time to break out
the bactine.
Well, at least he's dying
a millionaire.
I'll get
the first aid kit.
Push down on the wound.
Don't go!
For one brief,
shining moment
there was a camelot.
[Screams]
Ooh.
Put a tourniquet on his neck.
It's dark!
Ooh.
Kiss it and make it better.
Okay, bear down. Push.
[Shouts]
[Imitates heavy breathing]
Ah, it's a boy.
Congratulations.
Kawajiri! Kawajiri!
Hurry!
Kawajiri, you've never
given up on anything before.
Don't quit now, man.
Kawajiri! Kawajiri!
Tom and jerry? What?
Must have been
his favorite cartoon.
Ooh.
We had so much more to do.
He died as he lived.
Goofy.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, I hurt too, man.
He was unlucky.
Hey, I'm dealing with it.
Why can't you?
Can I have your watch?
So, lunch?
Don't cry.
It's no use.
Let's go.
Come on, man.
Yeah, we still got
a thousand wonderful hours.
Hey, let's put him
in a real scary pose.
Well, there's one
good thing at least.
We've got the opal.
We might as well get going.
Come on. You can't
bring him back to life.
Wuss.
Oh.
For safety,
I'll keep the opal. Hmm?
Yeah, I'm better now.
I'm all right.
Huh?
Hey, now.
Don't you trust me with it?
Well, I, uh...
Trust?
Hmm.
You can keep the opal.
I'll take the gun.
Sorry. There's a seven-day
waiting period on that gun.
Huh.
- Okay.
- Good deal.
One, two, three,
grab it.
- Wait.
- It's a football phone.
There might be other jewels
hidden in the cave.
Hmm.
I'll bet ours
isn't the only one.
Let's look,
now that we're in here.
Hey, steve, dead buddy,
do you think
that was smart of me
to get the gun
for the opal?
- I did it for you.
- [Imitates gun firing] Ooh!
Mm. Nipple?
Now to desecrate
the body.
Hey, that's my family.
Wonder what his sign was.
Scorpio?
[Laughter]
- With the bug and the--
- bing.
Tickle. Tickle.
No organ donor card.
[Imitates crying]
You know,
it's a brunswick.
I'm gonna bowl a 300
with this baby.
[Imitates crying]
Oh, hey,
that's not being supportive
of your friend's feelings.
At least he's lighting
a few candles for the guy.
Yeah, that's good.
I don't think
those are candles.
Sparklers.
Aw, the roadrunner's
never gonna fall for this.
[Mutters]
Huh?
Surprise!
Happy birthday to you.
Oh.
Filmed in sensurround.
Irwin allen.
Ah, shoot. I should have been
out of the cave first.
What was I thinking?
Note to myself--
get out of cave
before blowing it up.
Me and my booty.
Speaking of.
[Clears throat]
Easy on the vermouth, please.
And shaken, not stirred.
Please.
Oh, my salad.
I'm kidding.
Come here.
Now!
Guess not.
Saigon. Can't believe
I'm still in saigon.
Aw, he's missing the luau.
[Distant drums playing]
Oh, he can wait.
What am I doing
in this place?
We found you in time.
You would have been dead...
Minutes later.
But don't think that we
saved you out of kindness.
We simply
like our meat fresh.
It's fairly clear.
That friend of yours
found something in the cave.
Maybe.
He's gone. There's no need
to cover for him.
He betrayed you,
didn't he?
In a way.
He wanted
all of what we found.
An opal.
An oboe?
Opal?
Yes, huge.
It was as big of that.
Oh, you're thinking
of an ocarina.
My brother hid the opal
inside that cave 20 years ago.
Hmm.
It was to be shared
between us all.
Dad, dad,
he said "opal" to me.
I think
we're gonna be married!
Oh. I'm hungry.
Hey, you got any toast, or--
oh.
Man. I got to get a coat hanger
down this thing.
It's itching like a bear.
[Men singing outside]
Now what?
[Singing continues]
Get your popcorn, peanuts,
jewel thieves, frosty malts.
Bob hope's out there.
I think our friend's about
to become a casserole.
I better get a plan.
Quick.
I gotta think of something.
I gotta get this t-shirt
back to henry chinaski.
I told him not
to go in the cave,
and now look what happens!
Oh, it's all right.
Gauguin's here.
Tell him, dad.
[Clears throat]
What are they doing?
It's a long drum solo.
It's not your place to ask.
They are praying.
To ward off the curse
of the gods.
Curse of the gods?
Do not scorn what even science
cannot explain.
Something terrible
will happen...
Didn't something terrible
just happen?
Thousands and thousands of lives
depend on its return.
I see.
The opal's
worth that much, huh?
What you found
has no monetary value.
Oh, take the marbles
out of your mouth, old man.
So, uh, whose line is it?
Yours, mine?
Are we done?
Is that a wrap?
Oh, we're still rolling.
[Clears throat]
Doctor, let me get it back
from japan.
No, you can't.
You're a girl.
I will go.
Oh, no.
You have your patients here
who need you desperately.
I will go to japan.
You can't.
You've never
even been there.
It wouldn't be sane
for you to go off alone.
I have no choice.
I must try
to save these people.
My child.
Ask him to go with me.
Listen. The thing you found
wasn't a gem.
You still think
that it was an opal?
Well, yeah.
Who doesn't?
We're afraid
misfortune will follow.
That's why we are praying.
You don't expect me
to believe that story, do you?
Ha.
Something terrible
will happen now.
The legend warns
that the gods will be angry.
You've disobeyed the order.
None of us has ever dared
to visit the valley.
Ho, ho, ho.
You've touched something
evil and forbidden.
Oh, I suppose
you're perfect.
What it can be,
I don't know,
but it's certainly
not a gem.
Hey, it's the start
of bonanza.
Hoss, little joe.
Thank god they used downey.
The time tunnel. In color.
I think it's mackerel
with cheese sauce
and a dollop of cream.
Or maybe not.
It's out of focus,
whatever it is.
A piece of liver.
This movie is fascinating.
Not.
You know, I think
it's a ballpark frank.
See, it's plumping
as he cooks it.
Oh.
Well, I think we've
pretty much determined
that it is not an opal.
Ugh.
Nothing says loving
like something from the oven.
Caution--filling is hot.
And alive.
[With french accent]
And so the egg,
young and blue,
searches for its mother.
Hey, little muc-y guy.
[Horn echoing]
Hey, sonny rollins is practicing
on the bridge again.
Hey, doctor.
Play one more game, huh?
Well, I hope that
I'll be able to win it.
Somebody get that guy a bra.
It's getting late.
We aren't going to shore
till tomorrow.
Aren't we?
The sick bay door
won't open.
Hey, look. It's a clown.
Open it.
Put this flower there.
I want to give it
to your dead friend.
Not now.
Some other time.
Hey, it's the dj
from deee-light.
You see,
my father died on that island.
So your friend
doesn't seem
like a stranger to me.
Open it.
Please give him the key.
I got boardwalk,
park place.
Oh!
Hey, who took the tires
off the dock?
Next week on "voyage
to the bottom of the sea."
What's going on here?
Engine room.
Give me the engine room.
Captain. Captain.
Uh-oh.
Goodbye, mom. Bye.
Hey, jake and elwood.
Hmm.
Cab calloway.
That's a ship.
What's happening.
Toy boat.
Toy boat. Toy boat.
Hirata, you sure
they've got the opal?
All right, then.
Let me see it.
You're asking
a very high price.
Yes, yes.
I know.
Ooh, at 7:00 a.m.
the main hatchway caved in.
Wreck of
the ella fitzgerald.
Hey, adam clayton powell.
Abandon ship!
[All shouting]
Aah! Panic!
What's happened
to the ship?
It blew up.
Hey, it's funny girl,
and there's barbra streisand.
McHALE!
Taxi. Oh.
Cab! Going uptown.
Jeep? Oh.
Welcome to ellis island.
Your name is now bob smith.
Andolini?
No, you're now corleone.
And I think
I'll name you appetite.
Thank you. Hope you enjoyed
your norwegian princess cruise.
Take the ambulance
over there.
Take that blanket.
Oops. I wet 'em.
Hey, did you ever
see the movie papillon?
I--i saved this.
Hey, they're giving away
free clothes over there.
I was lucky.
Something important.
Something important too.
What do you got there?
Your friend's bones.
You can keep 'em, you fool.
- Huh?
- They're pigs' bones.
Wah, wah, wah.
Pigs' bones?
Excuse me. Have you
come from that ship?
I have.
Do you know
where keisuke is?
Who'd you say?
Casey kasem?
Uh, he was a seamen
on the same ship.
Uh, let me see.
Eh, let's see.
I'm a psychic.
The great carnac.
Let me see, um...
Onodera! Onodera.
- Huh?
- Hmm.
Thank heavens
you're all right.
[Mutters]
But where's my brother?
Keisuke.
Casey kasem?
Bad news.
What's happened to him then?
Sorry.
[British accent]
He's dead.
Huh?
He's...dead?
Mm.
He slipped and fell.
Onto some live grenades.
Shh.
Kawajiri too.
Kawajiri? Cowabunga.
I searched for them both.
Through the whole cave.
For about ten seconds.
But I couldn't
find their bodies.
It was terrible.
Did you find the gem?
Did you?
I wanna look at it.
Of course. I've got it.
Is it true? Is it?
Let me see it then.
The opal sank
when the ship did.
Hmm?
I was keeping it safe
by hiding it in my cabin.
I don't believe you!
Well,
I'm telling you the truth.
All right,
it wasn't my cabin.
The sea isn't very deep
right here.
A diver can retrieve it.
No, no, no.
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
No, no, no, no, no. No.
You're a fool to think
we'll ever get it back.
You call me
when I've found it.
Till then,
I'll keep my money.
Goodbye.
Well,
it's down to me and you
and me and part of your eye.
Believe me?
Hey! What's that?
It's your finger,
and it's pointing.
Dope.
Oh, it's the ghost
of esther williams.
It's--no, it's mr. Bubble,
and boy is he cheesed.
It's a mr. Bubble
pool party.
Help, police, there's a man
in the bathtub.
Stop, grandma.
It's me.
What'll we do?
We need more calgon.
There are two
japanese army jeeps
in the lot
with their lights on.
Oh!
Look at that!
Hi, there.
I'm a juicy new character.
Enjoy me.
I'm what's known
as the complication.
The antagonist, if you will.
Aah!
Well, for my first number,
I'd like
to crash a warehouse.
It's an old favorite.
I think you're gonna like it.
It goes
something like this.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I did that
on the sullivan show,
but, uh, they only filmed me
from the waist up.
They say I flipped 'em off,
but it's just the way
my fingers are constructed.
If gamera craves fire,
what does barugon crave?
Uh, ben and jerry's
cherry garcia.
Natch.
Hey,
I'm doing my own stunts.
If wholesome,
family entertainment
is old-fashioned
then call me old-fashioned.
Hey, hey,
look at the clown jeep.
Oh.
Come, tiny tim.
Oh, bless us, everyone.
Yeah,
let's get out of here!
Wait! Onodera!
Wait till
we get back to osaka.
What'd he say?
Well, roughly translated,
it means "beat cheeks."
Oh.
Hey, drag that nurse along.
She might come in handy.
Oh, he's leaking.
Ugh.
Like it so far? But wait.
There's more.
This serrated edge
will slice tomatoes so thin
you can see
right through them.
About this time,
most folks are wondering
am I a dog?
I don't even know.
Ruff ruff.
Just kidding.
Oh, no. He thinks
it's a giant fire hydrant.
Don't lift your leg, boy.
I think, uh...
Why don't you
treat yourself?
You're a growing monster.
Go ahead.
Whoa. He got that
from gene simmons.
I'm your boyfriend now.
Blagh!
- Time to go?
- Time to go.
- Aw.
- Come on.
I wanna watch the puppy.
Just a beer
and a bump sometimes.
Oh, but I never
really drink anything.
You know that.
I'll have the occasional
light beer,
and merle likes
his scotch, ya know.
But anyway,
you'll never believe
what margaret told me
about the steward boy.
Oh, I am dying.
Just tell me.
Apparently what he's into--
okay,
how was everything, ladies?
Oh, you really did a number
on this mexi-cita fajita
super bell grande treat-a,
didn't you?
Oh, it was good,
and so filling.
Oh, yes.
Everything's just wonderful.
I'm really full.
Okay, good.
Well, I'm gonna be heading back
to get the desert tray,
and, uh,
do you want anything?
Coffee, tea,
shot of tequila?
Huh?
[Laughter]
Heavens no. We're fine.
Thank you.
Okay, I'll be right back.
Excuse me.
He is super neat
and so creative.
Oh, honey, they all are.
This is my favorite place
to come.
Oh, not every day,
but, you know,
a special treat sometimes.
You see all the antiques
on the wall here?
Oh, I love them.
Oh, they do it up
so colorful.
You gotta get down here
on halloween sometime,
'cause they all dress up
in costumes
and it's super colorful
and so much fun.
Okay, here we are, girls.
Oh, my. Oh, we're
in trouble now, honey.
Now over here,
we've got tgi tokyo's
biggest seller.
Here it is. The chocolate
towering inferno,
and it is decadent.
But, uh, you probably
don't like chocolate, do you?
- Oh, no, I love chocolate.
- Yes.
I'm kidding. Of course
everyone loves chocolate.
Uh, this one here you probably
wouldn't be interested in.
I'm just kidding.
It's a little rich, you know.
But this is our apple double
murder suicide tort.
It's kind of spicy and it
has a little rum in it,
SO I'M GONNA HAVE
TO SEE YOUR IDs, GIRLS.
Oh, you are so sweet.
So sweet.
Anyway,
this last one over here
is too dense
for me to even pick up.
This is our vanilla
cross-country killing spree
with fudge sauce.
One bite of this
and you lock tongues with loki,
evil god
of strife and discord
on the seventh platform
of hell.
I'm just kidding.
It's a little rich.
Can I get you one?
Honey, that's the one
I'm gonna have there.
Oh, nothing for me, please.
And a diet pepsi please.
All right, that's good.
Uh, one of those
and a diet pepsi.
I'll get you a fork just in case
you wanna try it, okay?
- He knows me so well.
- He sure does.
- He's such a cute boy.
- Oh, say, waiter.
- Oh, waiter?
- Yeah.
Uh, could we have
separate checks please?
Uh, I'm sorry, ladies, we don't
to that here at tgi tokyo.
- Ah, what a jerk.
- No kidding.
- Uh, ladies...
- Yes?
- We have movie sign!
- Aah!
That was just delightful.
Oh, that was sweet.
Oh, you got any tums
in the car?
I got a little gas, I think.
I guess we'll have
to postpone the search
until this monster's dead.
We can't put it off forever.
It'll be too late.
The june wedding is so cliche.
...the police
and the insurance company
are bound to mess around
with that ship.
Ooh, that's good booze.
Then we'll never
get the opal back.
So we'll have to act now.
It's the only chance
we've got to find it.
First, we'll need money.
Oh, I've got quite a bit
of money put aside.
That's good. Is it in cash?
I have a dowry.
We could live with my folks.
And we can hire the diver.
Hirata! Hirata.
The monster
is getting nearer to osaka.
- What?
- Huh?
The radio says so.
It'll kill all of us.
Let's leave here.
Let's get out.
Fine, honey.
What time's dinner?
We having rice again?
We can't pull it up, because
we've got to leave osaka.
If we go now, we'll lose it.
After all the risks I've taken.
I'm leaving.
Let's go to kobe.
- It'll be safe there.
- Yeah.
No. I'm not going until
we've brought that opal up here.
This confusion's
just what we need.
Nobody'll notice.
- Not now.
- Fool. We've got to.
No, we'll have to give it up
for a little while.
I can't give it up.
Not after
I've killed two men.
- Huh?
- Oh?
- Onodera. Onodera.
- We can't wait longer.
Onodera,
what was that you said?
Tell me. You said
that you killed two men.
Uh, oh,
that figure of speech.
Metaphor. Ha. Teasing.
You killed them both?
Well,
not at the same time.
I only meant they've
given their lives for this.
- Liar.
- Pants on fire.
You murdered my brother
so that you'd have
the opal to yourself.
Of course not.
Maybe I did.
You killed them.
You killed them both
in cold blood.
No. No.
[Imitating choking]
Tiny tim, no!
Oh, whatever you do,
don't hit the inflatable
reindeer. Please!
Henry,
the boys are at it again.
Oh.
You killed him.
You killed my brother!
You dirty rat.
Stop it.
You're killing him.
Shouldn't one of them
know kung fu?
- Not enough room.
- Ah.
That's it.
Out you pixies go.
Through the door.
Out the window.
You're killing him!
Hey, she's got money on you.
Don't lose.
No! Please!
Hey.
Don't worry.
She's a stunt mom.
Ooh. Oh.
Ow.
Oh, great. Finish him off
with a bowling locker.
Oh, that had to hurt.
With his bad back?
...all residents
must evacuate osaka at once.
Do not delay.
Now where are those
raffle tickets?
Onodera. Save me.
Get me out of here.
Forget the lunch
and go for the wallet.
Mm-hmm.
Save me!
Let's see.
Pick six...
Thanks for a lovely dinner.
[All shouting]
Aren't you glad
you used dial?
Don't you wish
everyone did?
Whew.
Let's get out!
Smells like
a dead cat in there.
Nice wood grain.
Really nice.
She's wearing a garter.
Oh.
Very stylish shot, really.
Aw, joel,
can I have a puppy like that?
Please?
You know, he'd be perfect
for ring toss.
Look at the beak on him.
You folks gotta excuse me.
I'm not used to this city.
Hot child in the city.
Runnin' wild.
Lookin' pretty.
Hey, where are all
the nick gilder jokes?
Boy, let me tell you.
Poor suckers
chained to a desk
while I roam free.
Go figure.
You know, I miss
my hot wheels set.
Bye.
Toyland. Toyland.
I can't believe
I'm still in toyland.
A world of whimsy.
Oh, look at him go.
Good thing he's sporting
teflon, huh?
How about a tongue sandwich,
tokyo?
You know, you don't see that
a lot in nature.
No.
It's all christmasy!
Frosted mini tanks, gang.
Rosebud.
His tank was called rosebud.
Did you know that?
Ruined it.
Everything within reach
is immediately destroyed.
Hi, folks.
How's the shower, lady?
It's 10:00. Do you know
where your kids are?
I ate 'em!
Ha, I love that.
Property values plummet
when whole neighborhood
suffers from freezer burn.
Ooh.
Little nip in the air.
- Really.
- Huh?
Unusual weather
we're having.
It's a marshmallow world.
It's pretty!
[Goofy laughter]
A frozen pagoda treat.
Huh?
Ah, show me something
I haven't seen.
You know, I saw a wire.
That wrecks the whole thing.
- You mean this is fake?
- Yeah.
Oh, for crying out loud.
How about a little tongue,
scarecrow?
Let's see. That's called
french combat, isn't it?
Oh!
Abort mission.
Uh, we're taking orders.
Who wants a bear claw?
Oh, I'm not in this scene.
Wait a minute.
Mao is a toastmaster?
The monster can destroy
everything with its tongue.
You try saying that
without laughing.
...weapons are useless.
- Well then.
- Let's not send your men.
...next attack on it
from some distance.
Will that be safe enough?
Possibly. We do have one site
that's out of his range.
Right here. Where we have
our missile corps stationed.
Hey, that's ireland.
It'll be too far away.
The monster's tongue
cannot possibly reach it.
It's only a mile long.
Whoa.
Estes park, colorado,
meet the stinger, big bertha,
the gremlin.
He's dreaming of big,
mutated-armor-covered rabbits.
All right.
Whoa. Has that guy
been near radiation?
Having hot flashes.
The men have
completed preparation, sir.
- H!
[Laughter]
Hello ace awards, you two.
We are standing by
for orders, sir.
Right. Begin the attack.
- Morning.
- Oh, good morning.
- Hi, everybody.
- Ah, good morning.
Ugh.
Morning.
This is barugon.
Starting our broadcast day.
Wait a minute. Something's
rotten in osaka now.
He wakes up with the worst
breath of the millennium.
Wonder if they'll
call off school today.
It's the rockettes.
Whoo!
Legs up, girls.
What? A spine
in technicolor spectrum ray?
Ah, it's a skittles
commercial.
Oh, yeah. From hell.
Oh, I'm sure
he could do that.
How do he know?
Bing.
Hmm.
Well. That went well.
Gamera's attracted
by any form of heat energy.
And I'm attracted
to bea arthur. Go figure.
...so gamera's
flying toward it over osaka.
Hey.
Ooh.
He's becoming a starburst
fruit chew before my eyes.
Oh.
Gamera's melting
like a lemon drop
high above the chimney tops.
Uh, sir,
it's not an escalator.
- Whoa!
- Aah!
Right in the ears.
The attack
by the missile corps
have proved unsuccessful
against barugon's rainbow.
And here we end the 9:00 p.m.
news bulletin.
What, do you they got radios
in their kids' heads?
- What?
- ...As they happen.
In the meantime,
some music by yanni.
You know, it's unsettling,
but beautiful.
Quietly disturbing.
What a dismal place
to be hold up with...
No, you can't
play your accordion.
...stuck here
like a bunch of animals.
Huh? Why are they
making all this fuss
about a phony
little monster, huh?
Why?
Why don't you shut up?
You make me sick.
[Imitates vomiting]
Oh, not really.
Oh, reverend moon's
holding a prayer and share.
Gamera is vulnerable
to the cold.
He has been frozen powerless
by this new monster.
Named clarence birdseye.
But the second monster
is unharmed,
and now the authorities
are without the means...
My god.
It's barugon.
Barugon?
It is.
I thought it was
another monster,
but it's my barugon.
Attention please.
Oh, god, could he kiss.
...airlines flight ab-711...
Karen.
...san francisco, seattle,
and vancouver
is about to leave.
Passengers
will please proceed...
Karen, what's wrong?
Are you ill?
I'm carrying
barugon's child.
They've come too late.
I just couldn't believe
that your story was true.
I'm responsible
for bringing this.
[All]
Aah!
Don't do that.
As soon as it's possible
to get there.
You know of a way
to get rid of it?
Yes, I do.
I've got the answer here.
Let's hurry
to stop all this horror.
Okay. I'm with you.
Whoa.
Hey!
Gee, lay off
for a minute, would ya?
Crying out loud.
Oh, that's a bridge
over troubled models.
That's cute.
Oh, and I can't even
get this open. D'oh!
Hey, louie,
you still okay in there?
[Muffled]
Yeah, I'm okay.
- Huh?
- You.
Onodera.
Oh, it's with the thing,
and the...
[Nervous laughter]
Sorry about the thing with the--
but it's a good thing.
Assassin.
[Imitates choking]
Look at that lobe.
Man, as leopold too.
We'll be able
to find the opal.
You fool.
It wasn't a jewel.
- What's that?
- It was a monster's egg.
[Laughs]
Don't be ridiculous.
Good one.
I tell you that the opal
is the egg out of which
the monster hatched!
It's our fault.
You and I brought
this destruction here.
We're going to kill that monster
before it's too late.
Don't give me that story.
No, here's one.
Two chinamen walk into a bar.
Ha.
I've just come
from my brother's.
He and his wife
are both dead.
Their house burned.
Someone saw you
running out of their house
just before the fire.
You!
Hey, I was in austria
during the whole thing.
Honest.
Not my fault.
You liar!
Pants on fire.
[Imitates choking]
Oh, that's good.
Hit him with wicker.
Not the johnnie walker!
Hey, uh, honey,
you can jump here any time.
Jump in. Come on.
Thank you. Finally.
There we go.
Uh-oh. Ginsu 2000.
Cuts through lead pipe
and still disembowels.
Yeah. Feel like
I'm watching mannix.
Dun, dun, dun, dun.
You'd think they'd be able
to use kung fu or something.
Yeah. Where's bruce lee
when you need him?
Sucker punch.
Ow.
Ah, you're lucky
my chick's here, man.
That's it.
Don't try to understand him.
Just ride and rope
and brand him.
Now, when I left
the house this morning
I had a short rope,
a long rope,
and a medium-sized rope.
Now,
I don't know any tricks--
sorry. Sorry.
Can you put your finger
there for a sec?
Time on that?
Time please?
Oh, he's been shooting up.
Huh?
What in the world?
Hold on here.
Hey.
Wait a min...
This is one weird scene.
Ugh.
Uh, you got a little, uh...
Ah, forget it.
You are one spooky chick.
Do you mind if I don't
call you again? Ugh.
He's just her type too.
"A" positive, that is.
You know you're beautiful
when you're bloody.
I'm all right.
Let's go.
Hey. Please help me.
Let's go. Let's go.
Hey. Wait.
I--i apologize.
Help me.
I'm trying to say I'm sorry.
Poor guy.
So...
Hey, her hair got shorter.
May I tell you something,
if you please?
- No.
- Yes, go ahead.
I sucked his blood,
and I liked it.
Barugon is a land animal.
Once in the water,
his cells melt.
Purple blood
flows out quickly.
At least that is the legend
our ancestors
have passed down to us.
- His strength goes rapidly.
- Hmm.
But also his tongue
would become paralyzed
and therefore harmless,
and it would be easy
to approach him
and destroy him then.
Hmm,
like the wicked witch, eh?
We must lure barugon
to the water
and then
he'll drown himself.
It's the answer.
And how do we lure him?
With this.
- Hmm.
- Dove bars?
Oh.
[Engines whooshing]
Jet traffic.
Say...
We have preserved this huge
diamond in our village
for many generations.
But what has the diamond
got to do with barugon?
Ah, keep your shirt on.
It's cubic zirconia.
This'll draw him on
irresistibly.
We can use it
to lure him into the water?
Does your village have many
diamonds this size?
Simmer down,
you gold digger. Gee.
Just this one is left.
Every thousand years
a monster such as this
is born in my village.
That's a long
gestation period.
Each time one is born,
another of our diamonds
must be sacrificed.
It is dropped into the lake
to lure the monster
to its death.
If that's the case,
I realize how precious
this last diamond is.
Are you sure
that barugon will respond
as the legend has predicted?
If you don't believe in it,
you are doubting the gods.
Whoa. Guess I stepped on
a few toes there.
Sorry.
We haven't time to waste.
It's the only idea
that hasn't been tried.
Oh, what about the "z" plan?
We'll put it to work at once.
Sorry.
In which direction
shall we guide you?
Is there a large lake
to sink him in?
There's biwa lake.
I can't untie it.
Well, cut it with that knife.
There.
Geishas who love too much.
Hurry.
Oh, the rope,
not my wrist.
Careful.
...the safest place
to deposit him.
Authorities hope
that the 5,000 karat diamond...
That's it. Talk it over
with jack daniels.
Wow.
What an incredible scheme.
A 5,000 karat diamond,
to be sunk in biwa lake,
just to get the monster.
What?
Are you sure?
Of course. A native girl
brought it to japan.
Who told you?
The radio announced it.
Was she in
bride of frankenstein?
Those natives
did have a jewel.
Worth more
than I'd ever dreamed of.
But daddy needs his medicine.
Ah.
Last call.
All right.
So I'll get it.
Want a drool bucket?
Oh, right on me.
In a final attempt
to rid japan of barugon,
operation diamond
is put into effect.
They offered him a cocktail.
A 5,000 karat diamond
is used
to trick the monster
into abandoning
his natural environment, land,
for the waters of lake biwa.
Scenic lake biwa.
Yeah, right.
I'm heading off to a lake?
You think
I was born yesterday?
Oh, wait. I was.
Traffic on the i-94 outbound
is still bumper to bumper
during the sundown slowdown.
[Roars]
Want it.
Barugon, are you up to one
of your little schemes again,
you little conniver?
Get me.
I'm carol channing.
No, he's cuter
than carol channing.
Oh.
You know,
don't you think a disco ball
would have been
a little cheaper?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, look.
There's liz taylor.
No, he's smaller
than liz taylor.
Come on. Be nice.
Oh, fun.
What's wrong?
Keep dangling
and shaking it.
I think he's going for it.
Try jerk bait.
I--i gotta go walkies.
Ugh.
No use.
He won't follow.
We've failed.
Here's one for you.
Why did I cross the road?
There's no right answer.
I don't even know.
[Laughter]
Now what?
We smell one.
Shame, shame, all around.
I don't understand.
Overpass?
I don't think so.
If this legend
that the villagers believe in
- is really true...
- And I doubt it.
Then kindly tell me why
he disregarded the diamond.
He didn't like the cut,
the clarity,
the color, or karat.
I suspected the validity
of her story
from the first time
that I heard her speak.
It was too much
of a fairytale
and we should never
have listened to her.
Aw, jeez,
heap more shame on her.
Besides, I doubt very much
that there was a real diamond.
If a gem that size
existed anywhere in the world,
there'd be reports of it.
So it failed.
But it isn't her fault.
She was doing her best
to give you her help.
- Listen.
- You're just trying to lay
all the blame on us.
[All]
Yeah, and scarecrow's brain!
Just remember
that it was your greed
that brought all this misery
upon us in the first place.
You got me.
But still.
We tried to help.
Be quiet!
And go to your room.
I acted shamefully,
I know.
She's blameless.
She gave you one possible plan.
It's just been a foolish
waste of precious time.
I know,
but it isn't her fault.
Die! Die! Die!
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
Areas to the west
have been moved...
I have to go now.
To the little
general's room, you know.
He hurts me so.
There, there, dear.
Let's get you a pint
of fresh type "a."
Hmm?
Oh, get a room.
Mm-hmm.
I'll repeat that message...
Uh, I hate to pull rank
on you, son,
but, uh, hmm.
In fact, we're very much
obliged to you.
You tried your best.
She is a wild tigress,
isn't she?
Excuse me.
This gentleman is dr. Sato.
Hello.
Ah. How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
- Good.
You?
This time you've got
some real trouble.
Oh, we certainly have.
Think you can help us?
Have you got some
suggestions to make?
I'm glad I stopped by.
On my way over here...
I believe that barugon
was exposed to an infrared ray
while still an egg.
And I believe for every
drop of rain that falls
a flower grows.
You see,
I was on the ship
that brought the egg
here to japan.
Onodera. He was the man
who found the egg,
thinking it was a gem.
He was then receiving
infrared-ray treatment
for athlete's foot.
What's so absorbing, junior?
Now it seems quite possible
that he forgot
to turn the lamp off.
It was probably directed
towards the egg.
Hey, look back there.
It's cary grant
in the faberge years.
At very close range,
and over quite a substantial
period of time.
Castro's there too.
...speeded up considerably
the growth of the monster.
Then that explains it.
Now I understand
what's happened.
The legend says barugon
should take ten years
to reach his present size.
Ah, indeed.
Are you certain that it should
take ten years to mature?
Yes. I am.
Barugon is really a freak
with an abnormal body.
I know the feeling.
That's something
we doctors can explain.
If an expectant mother
is exposed to radioactivity,
a freak may be born.
Like rick james?
So then that's why it showed
no interest in the diamond.
That's right.
He's a super freak.
Listen. Now that we know
that it's a freak,
isn't there some different way
that we should attack it?
It's herbie!
Expose the diamond
to the infrared ray.
Will that do us any good?
No, but it will
pad the film out a little bit.
...barugon must therefore
respond favorably to it.
Yeah, I'm buying this
big time.
Now then. Perhaps the diamond,
if radioactive,
will be effective.
Barugon may respond to it
as you first hoped.
Barugon, that's me.
Karen, is there any way to make
him stay where he is now?
Uh, we could staple him
to the floor.
There's one possibility.
Our villages have all
been praying for rain.
If heaven cares,
it will send us rain.
Why rain?
You got a better idea?
Water will weaken him.
Our legend says that the monster
cannot move while it rains.
She kiddin' us?
But why wait for the gods.
Isn't it easy now
to create rain?
Heck, my aunt could do it.
We'll produce it, all right.
You direct.
Manmade rain
from helicopters.
A flight of helicopters
is sent to fly over barugon...
[Coughing]
...spraying onto him
manmade rain.
A mist-like liquid,
which it is hoped,
will arrest
the monster's movements.
Send in the clouds.
The rain should make barugon
unable to exhale
his freezing vapor,
thus rendering him harmless.
Or at least drowsy
and unable to operate
heavy machinery.
[With british accent]
Well, could be worse.
How?
Could be rainin'.
Whoa.
Catch the drops on your tongue.
It's fun.
You know, uh, rainy days
and mondays always get me down.
It's true.
Poppies.
Poppies will make him sleep.
Well, let's head over
to the bozo drum!
Hoo-hoo!
This machine is called
a death ray projector,
and a ruby is put in
to act upon the light molecules.
Thus the waves of light
are broken down.
- Right now...
- Oh, just get on with it.
You can see the machine
is in the experimental stage,
and cannot be put
to practical use.
But now possibly
we can employ the diamond
- instead of the ruby.
- Neat.
- Let's insert it.
- Together.
And try its effectiveness.
You're trying
my effectiveness.
We're anxious
to try it out at once.
Turn it onto barugon
and see if it works.
Okay.
He's sleeping. Somebody
put his hand in warm water.
Darn poachers.
Well, there goes our ride.
Hi.
Why, barugon,
you're crying.
Fake.
I'm just resting my eyes.
Oh, look at him.
He's all over the road.
Oh, no. Oh, and here comes
a hapless family
on a sunday ride.
Um, honey, there's something
in the road ahead.
What is this,
the universal tour?
Begin.
The beguine.
[Hums]
Ooh.
Right. Move forward.
Love is kinda crazy with
a spooky little girl like her.
Mm-hmm.
Hmm?
Oh, company.
My favorite snack.
Karen, got it?
She never lost it.
Ah, be careful.
Music goes round and round
and comes out here.
Whoa.
Look, he's leaking.
No, he's just dieseling.
Oh.
Preparations ready, sir.
Good. Start.
Oh. Begin.
We'll start.
- Get going.
- Engage.
- Make it so.
- Now.
- Fire.
- Initiate.
- Go.
- Time to get it moving.
Whatever happened to gamera?
You know,
he got top billing.
He must have a really good
agent, I think.
I suppose so.
Now...
He's moving!
It's moving!
Hey!
Good. Drive on.
There's that glowing guy again.
Once he gets
into the spotlight,
we're expecting him to do
a couple jazzy show tunes.
[Dramatic music]
Spotlight dance.
Barugon.
Doing the dog.
Good.
Well said.
Ah, you know,
I was singing for the people.
They were crawling at me.
They were throwing...
She's got the flare-nostril look
I love so much.
Oh, now watch.
He'll have black rings
around his eyes
when he pulls
the binoculars down.
Come on, here it goes.
Here it goes--aw.
Oh, no!
What's wrong?
Everything.
We gotta lengthen the movie.
I'm so embarrassed.
Ruff. Ruff.
Let's get out of here!
Right!
[Engine struggling]
Won't start, huh?
Mommy!
Mommy, mommy,
it's your boy!
Oh, no.
He's doing jolson.
Turn out the light.
Quickly.
Okay.
Hey.
Hey, guess you saw it.
Right.
Now I'll do eartha kitt.
♪ C'est si bon... ♪
Don't go too close.
Be careful.
It's going to be dangerous.
No.
Now. Switch on.
For action!
And now I'd like to tell a few
things about show business...
About the time
that I met this man
that was coming to me
on broadway.
Right. Board now.
Yes, sir.
Orders came down.
- Don't say it.
- Right.
So herbert norville
comes to me,
and he says that...
Commence progress, now!
To the lake!
Yay, we're all going
to the lake!
Yay! Whoopee!
Bring the inflatable dog.
I'm not going in the tunnel.
Well, I'm sure not
going to lose that diamond.
Time to blow.
No, don't go.
You can't take such a risk.
Let go of me
and stay out of my car.
Please don't go.
Come back here.
Get away!
No, don't go. Don't go!
[Humming]
Oh, hey, crow,
anymore brewskis
in the cooler there?
Uh, no. How about
a frozen daiquiri convection?
Oh, sure.
That sounds great.
Boy, it sure is
a nice day today, hmm?
Yeah, like a warm
summer night back home.
You know, back on earth
we used to hang out
at the beach all the time.
Or else we'd go to the drive-in,
which was really fun.
The drive-in?
Oh, yeah.
We'd all pile into the car
and head out
to the old lucky twin
back in buffalo
on route five.
Oh. Joel, tell us
about the movies again, hmm?
Well, my little
cinematic sidekicks,
you know, in those days,
we had real stars.
We didn't need dialogue.
We had faces.
Oh, kinda like this gamera film,
huh, joel?
Oh, yeah, but that's--
this film certainly
had a lot of faces.
I'll give you that
for free.
But these films never seem
to have any big-name stars.
Well, that's where
you and I split the dog,
my little red pal.
Uh, this film is packed
with celluloid heroes,
and they never
feel any pain.
Huh.
It was a magic time
in hollywood.
Stars jumped at the chance
to appear in a gamera film.
Here, I'll show you.
Cambot, do it like I like it.
See, check it out.
There's edward g. Robinson,
fresh from his role
in soylent green.
Now shut up and eat
your soylent green, see.
Soylent green
is made from people.
Yeah, whatever.
Here's elvis costello
making his screen debut.
I don't know. Looks more
like marshall crenshaw to me.
Or arnold stang.
Oh, yeah, look.
Here's peter ustinov.
Hey, it looks "ustinov"
like him to me.
Uh, yeah. And here
we have lon chaney, jr.
Uh, right. Sure, joel.
That's--
hey, let me finish.
Next we have steve allen.
Claude akins
and harrison ford.
Oddjob and willem dafoe,
robert blake
and willem dafoe.
Uh, joel, are you okay?
Hey, shut up.
Hank williams, jr.
Jerry lewis
and willem dafoe.
Uh, joel, when you went
to the drive-in,
did you spend a lot
of time to the trunk?
Did I mention
jerry to you bots?
You guys
probably don't know him
hardly working
or cracking up,
but, oh, lady mister
heeminy homen,
what in the hey? Oh...
Please help me.
Uh...
Uh, folks,
we'll be right back.
Sorry you had to see this.
[Whistles]
Oh, boy.
Ugh.
Think I got a sunburn.
Told you there's a lot
of stars in this movie.
Neat.
Careful, robin.
Both hands on the bat rope
at all times.
It's you.
Why are you here?
- I'm getting that diamond.
- Figures.
Hasn't your greed
caused enough grief already?
Why don't you
get out of here?
Oh, boy.
You know, guys,
I'm starting to doubt
their friendship.
Aah!
Crying out loud.
[Woman screams]
Humans.
Who can understand 'em?
Go figure.
What's going on?
Hey, sergeant, go and check.
- Doctor. Doctor.
- Give me the news.
I have a right
to get at that diamond.
No, you haven't.
Dance. Dance.
The lambada.
- The forbidden dance?
- Yeah.
Or else I'll shoot.
- Hi.
- Oh, there.
[Engine revs]
Ah, wait, wait.
I don't have my skis up.
Aah!
[Roars]
Uh-oh.
Oh, that's giving him
the raspberry.
Help me!
I've been frenched to death!
I call that a manwich.
[Laughs]
Just something to hold him over
until he gets to osaka.
Now you can't go back
in the water
for another hour.
Remember that.
Why are they so sad?
That's the guy
that killed his brother.
Well, there's something
about watching a man
get tongued to death.
Well, that's the way
I want to go. Whoo!
Well, that's it.
We're licked.
Sorry. Sorry! Sorry.
That's what you get.
Mom, mom, watch me dive!
Throw me a stick.
I'll catch it.
The plan has failed.
Barugon has swallowed
the massive diamond.
Our only hope
is that he'll pass it.
The only method
that we have left
to get rid of the monster
has now been...
O.a.k.
- Get the helicopters.
- Sir.
Have them produce rain
so barugon can't move.
- There is no other way.
- Sir.
I love the theater.
I do.
Meanwhile, at a storage unit
outside of osaka...
Hmm?
What are they,
at a columbo tryout?
It's useless
looking around here.
We won't find a thing.
Yeah,
the audience has left too.
Ever since I was a child,
I've been told
of the disastrous rainbow
that the monster can make.
Oh, what's she going on about?
Because one is born
only after each thousand years,
I wanted to see it
with my own eyes.
I was too young
the last time.
No matter how
terrifying it was.
Mm-hmm.
[Hums]
Oh, sorry.
I didn't know.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't listening.
Did you say something?
No one will ever be able
to get rid of it now.
It's our punishment
for wanting so much wealth.
So what's gonna happen
to donald trump?
Yes.
Yes, she's buying it.
If only
I could work up a tear.
Oh.
She's going for it.
Wait a minute.
A napkin?
That gives me an idea.
Honey, you're brilliant.
[Sniffs]
Ugh.
Hmm?
Now, what are these?
Snap zooms.
They look like
rearview mirrors.
They're all that's left
of the jeep.
Are these questions
rhetorical?
...along with everything else.
They appear to be impervious.
Neat.
See what that means?
There's a weakness
in the rainbow.
And there's more of us!
Oh. Oh.
Now, doctor,
isn't the rainbow similar
to a death ray projector?
Well, it's kind of a reach,
but maybe.
I believe that's right.
Yes!
- Seems logical.
- Sure.
When the rainbow
hit the mirror,
it seems
to have been reflected
in just the way light is.
It wasn't harmed.
Because the energy
didn't penetrate it.
- Ah, I see.
- Yes.
- Reflected.
- Kill him. Oh.
The principal itself's really
a simple-enough one.
Hmm.
You may have hit on
something important.
But will this help us?
Can we use it against barugon?
No, but it's something to do.
Yes, sir.
I'm an amateur
in these matters,
but I have an idea.
Hmm?
Here,
now hold out your arm.
These flames can reach
an extremely intense heat.
They can even melt steel.
And yet, the stove itself
is quite unaffected
by all this heat.
Now why?
- Ho!
- Aah!
Don't...
Jeez.
The flames are ejected
outwards away from it.
But if they're turned in,
onto the burner itself,
what would happen then?
Oh, great. We're taking
a shop course all of a sudden.
Now i'm, uh, gonna make
a bird house for you folks.
- So you see?
- I made a flute.
...by its own flame.
When exposed to it.
Mm-hmm.
In the same way,
barugon can be destroyed.
Uh, come again?
Do we need to know this
for the test?
What do you think, sir?
You're toasted, aren't you?
That's quite an idea.
But surely it's impossible
to apply it here.
On barugon.
Why can't you
ever support me?
These mirrors.
We'll make a mirror large enough
and reflect his rainbow
onto him.
So, in theory,
barugon will be made to die
by his own rainbow.
Yeah, if that makes it work
for you. Of course.
Hmm.
- How very fitting.
- Ironic. I love it.
All right. Please get ready
to carry it out.
Get your costumes on.
So the microwave antenna
at the summit of mt. Kashika
is turned into a mirror,
in readiness for
operation rearview mirror.
Giant shredded wheat
is deployed.
Hundreds of workmen
are employed,
treating everything that holds
the mirrors in place
with a mercury preparation.
Tanks of windex are commissioned
by the government.
Kids are told by the thousands
not to smudge the mirrors.
At the same time,
action is being taken
to keep barugon in one spot.
George winston music
is played for him.
Preparations for operation
rearview mirror
have been completed.
The ground force is making use
of all its most
advanced weapons
in the attack
against barugon.
It is hoped that in this way
barugon will be angered.
And maybe a little put-out.
He will respond by sending out
his most powerful weapon--
- the rainbow.
- Of forgiveness.
Left by 300 degrees.
300 "degwees"?
"Woger."
Oh.
Down 28 degrees,
five seconds.
Heck of a tan
in that thing.
Stop. Correct range.
"Cowwecting" range, sir.
35, sir.
Right!
We're ready now.
Everything's in place to begin.
Doctor. Won't it be better
to wait until night
when we can see the rainbow?
I agree. We'll wait.
You know,
no one in my organization
has ever talked to me like that.
I like it.
[Imitating dramatic music]
I love it so.
[Dramatic music continues]
Oh.
Grand canyon suite.
There's no one up there.
No workmen or others.
Oh, no. Everything
at the antenna
is done by remote control.
I like your shirt.
It's kind of drapey.
Fire!
What now? I was posing
for crying out loud.
Uh, what was that about
repositioning the tanks?
Too late.
Can't run
from the rainbow.
- Mm-mm.
Frosted lucky charms.
Oh.
Ah, that's a cheap shot.
Ooh. Can you imagine
how that must smell?
- Ugh.
- Yeesh.
Ah, you know what really
burns my butt? Me.
That's cute.
Oh. Oh, hot. Oh, hot.
Oh, water. Water. Ooh.
[Hissing]
Aah.
Ooh.
Barugon's dead.
And garson's got him!
I think so.
Uh-huh.
He's dead.
You've killed him.
[Whispering]
I'm faking.
Shh.
Oh, this is gonna be
just like fatal attraction.
I know it.
Oh, what, is david lynch
directing now?
Suppurating fistulas
made from delicious
smucker's grape jelly.
Ugh.
[Clears throat]
Oh.
We just gave him a rash.
We failed. The rays weren't
powerful enough for it.
We've got to try again?
- Huh?
Yeah, you've got a dragon.
We must arouse him.
Hey, I listened
to the diamond thing,
but I am not
going to arouse him.
Barugon won't send out
another rainbow.
But why not?
Why not, karen?
I've grown up
in the jungle.
And I've lived amongst
the wild animals.
So?
So I know about their ways.
When an animal has once been
hurt by its own mistake,
it will never make
the same mistake again.
Not like us.
What she says is right.
It will never
send another rainbow.
Everything's in the toilet.
Operation rearview mirror
is at an end.
So let's go eat.
Who's hungry?
You buyin'?
Oh, no.
There's nothing we can do.
That's the spirit.
Nothing.
[Imitates crying]
Ah, shut up,
you pathetic bastard.
Get up!
Quit your crying.
Ah, you're nothing
but a gal darn coward.
Give me something
to slap him with.
But now, the buildings
frozen by barugon
have begun to thaw.
The ice melts away
from osaka castle.
Gamera has regained
consciousness.
And his pilot has re-lit.
Ah.
[Claps] Hey, are those
lee press-on nails?
Finally, a fight.
[Screeches]
How about a little
death bite on the neck?
[Laughs]
Whee.
Hey, bite this.
You mean like this?
I am wired.
He is, too.
[Roars]
Hey, hey, hey, you kids.
No splashing. Come on.
Hey, this water got warm
all of a sudden.
Marion, don't look
at the light, marion.
Look away.
[Screeches]
If you think of them as two guys
in rubber suits, it's real sad.
Yeah.
Rub my tummy.
[Laughter]
And out from the lizard
came a bubblin' crude.
Bile, that is.
Texas tea.
Oh, no. I don't wanna
get my hair wet.
Ooh.
Oh, look.
He's in the water.
Mm.
I'm here, steve.
It just may succeed.
It's a crazy idea,
but it just...Might...Work.
Oh, that's...
He's drowning
in is own gravy.
Ugh.
Hey, that fluoride treatment
shows he's really
needing to floss.
By this time, my lungs
were aching for air.
That is the last time
you can ever do that.
Don't hit.
Or yell.
Hurts, huh?
We die together, my friend.
Come on now.
Fight.
You've never given up
on anything in your life.
Now fight!
Hey, it's the...
A night the lights
went out on barugon.
Oh, no. She said he wouldn't
do another rainbow.
Hey, it's stopping now.
Barugon's finished.
He's completely defeated.
Then why do I
feel so empty?
Barugon's finished!
[All chattering]
Victory...
Oh, give her a kiss,
you big lug.
Come on.
[Laughs]
Little sugar on the jaw.
- He's finished.
- Let's go home.
You know,
shouldn't they kill gamera
now that they
got him right there?
Not a bad idea.
I don't know.
Call me prudent.
You know,
after the thrill is gone,
we're left
with the cold reality
that the chase
was all we ever had.
My great expedition
was a disaster.
Yep. Uh-huh.
All that way,
just to bring back anguish.
But you did your best
to help when you found out.
Then you'll have me?
It was you
who gave unselfish help.
Yep, you're right.
It was me.
I've learned
we should never let greed
direct our actions.
Yeah, but let's pick out
my ring first.
Karen, I'll take you home.
Back to your peaceful village.
Will you?
I feel so absolutely alone
right now.
Solipsism
is its own reward.
...my brother's dead.
Gosh,
your hand is clammy.
I could never love you.
Don't make me laugh.
You're not alone.
Aw.
Hey, there's, like,
eight hands down there.
Hey, get your hands
out of there.
[Imitates bones cracking]
You're squeezing too hard.
Your grip...
[Dramatic music]
[Imitates music]
And so we wave goodbye
to our friends.
Back to the ocean.
The source of all credits.
Gamera will be back in
"support your local sheriff."
Nobody knows why.
Oh, sandy frank.
I don't think
I've seen his name before.
Goodnight, everyone.
Enjoy the buffet.
We should get out of here.
Come on.
I'm gonna stick around.
I wanna see
how this turns out.
Oh, we should go.
It's just water crow.
You can stay just
a little bit longer, okay?
Mucho agua.
Crow, if you stay in too long,
you'll get wrinkly, dear.
[Imitating music]
Come on. Come on.
Whaa!
Ah, gee, joel, that wasn't
much of a gamera movie.
Yeah, I mean, gamera was hardly
in the movie at all,
yet he gets top billing.
Why's that, hmm?
Well, you see,
uh, in this film,
gamera wanted to spend a lot
more time behind the camera.
Oh.
See, yeah, and that's how
it all worked out.
You see, in hollywood,
gamera is considered
a triple threat--
a performer,
director, and monster.
Oh, kinda like
barbara streisand.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, you'll read about
the whole story
of gamera versus barugon
in this new book,
you'll never eat this town
for lunch again!
See, it's all in there.
That's really interesting.
You know, when it comes
to behind-the-scenes stories
about monster movies,
I'd like to read more about it.
Exactly, tom.
Reading opens up
a wonderful world
of whimsy and enchantment,
grades three to five.
Oh, I wanna read that one.
Hey, hollywood barugon:
The seamy
side of monster movies.
That's really neat.
The next one looks good too.
The best places
to eat japanese.
Ooh, how about that?
How to destroy a city
without really trying.
Yeah, next one,
the oldest-living
japanese mutant tells all.
Move your hand.
And this one's great
for kids,
the fabulous
where's barugon books.
Delightful.
You know,
there's a lot of great
also books on tape
about monsters.
I was just
about to ask about those.
This one's the velveteen turtle
read by meryl streep.
Let's listen to that one,
cambot.
And so the velveteen turtle
said to the little toy soldier,
"you're not like
the other toys, are you?
"You're different.
"That is why
I am going to kill you.
Why? Because you
are going to die."
- Yeah.
- That's delightful.
Very touching.
And then there's
sharp tongue: A memoir,
as read by barugon.
Let's hear that one,
cambot.
[Creature growling]
Hey,
what are these books, joel?
Less than zero,
I am not spock,
tekwars
by william shatner.
Oh, these are--
an actor publishes a novel
tonight on emergency 911.
These are just mine
over there.
Why don't we, uh,
read a letter, guys?
Oh, why not?
That sounds good to me.
Uh, let's put that
on still store there.
Anyway,
this is from joe karnes
of naperville, illinois.
Joe, uh, writes,
"dear joel and gang on mst,
"I really like your show.
"My favorite people are crow,
tom servo, gypsy,
cambot, and you."
That's just about all of us,
isn't it?
"I don't like
your bosses too much."
We don't either.
"Frank is kind of a crybaby,
"and dr. Forrester
yells at frank too much.
"I'm 12-years-old and watch
your show all the time.
"I love
the invention exchange.
"Y'all make
terrific inventions.
Hope to see
more of your show."
Let's put that
up on the screen.
Tell 'em where
they can write, tom.
They can write
to the mystery science theater
information club...
[Mumbles]
Do it today.
What do you think, sirs?
Funny you should mention
books, bubbie.
I asked frank
to pick me up a book
to read at the beach
this weekend.
Uh, what did you get, frank?
Oh, you're gonna love it.
This is great.
It's the stand
by stephen king.
This is the new uncut version,
which contains
all the passages
that were cut
from the restored version.
It's really great.
You're gonna really enjoy that.
Oh, thank you, frank.
Push the button, frank.